<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-11-25T00:09:47+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Astri’s Blog</title><subtitle>A Blog to share my experiences</subtitle><author><name>Astri Lestari</name></author><entry><title type="html">Obrolan pembuka mengenai Akreditasi</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/11/24/first-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Obrolan pembuka mengenai Akreditasi" /><published>2017-11-24T21:45:13+07:00</published><updated>2017-11-24T21:45:13+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/24/first-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/11/24/first-post.html">&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: justify&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sekadar Informasi, Ini adalah tulisan ketiga saya. Pertama saya nulis itu jika memang moodnya lagi bagus dan lagi ingin nulis. Mungkin catatan nanti saya-Link kan jika mau baca, itu sebenenrnya tulisan iseng dan gak penting sekali yang isinya penuh dengan kesedihan alias depresi. Kedua, mengenai Artikel Ilmiah tentang Diabetes Melitus dan kebetulan dapat Juara pertama di Persadia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kembali ke judul diatas, tujuan saya menulis di blog ini adalah membahas tentang akreditasi Puskesmas. Apa yang terlintas di benak Anda bagi yang belum terpapar dan sedang mempersiapkan akreditasi Puskesmas? Sebelum menjurus mengenai cerita saya tentang pengalaman Akreditasi, saya akan bercerita terlebih dahulu mengenai latar belakang yang mungkin ada sedikit hubungan dengan yang namanya Akreditasi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jujur, percaya atau tidak, saya mendengar akreditasi Puskesmas itu sekitar bulan Mei 2017 karena kebetulan saya dipindahkan ke Puskesmas yang sebelumnya saya bekerja di RSUD sebagai dokter Fungsional yang sehari-hari hanya melayani pasien di Poli, IGD, dan Ruang rawat inap.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Mungkin Anda juga akan bertanya, “kan sayang banget dari RSUD kok dipindahkan ke Puskesmas?” Jadi begini ceritanya, saya adalah Dokter PTT Daerah sejak 2016, karena RSUD itu baru dibuka. Bangunan RSUD Tipe D itu adalah bekas Puskesmas Kecamatan ‘P’ disana. Setelah selesai dibangun, RSUD membutuhkan banyak dokter umum saat itu, maka oleh Dinas Kesehatan Daerah saya ditempatkan di RSUD dahulu. Setahun kemudian, Puskesmas Kecamatan sudah mendapatkan tempat sementara untuk beroperasi, maka saya dipindahkan ke Puskesmas ‘P’ karena saya tetap memilih mempertahankan status PTTD saya dibanding kontrak di RSUD. Puskesmas dan RSUD letaknya tidak berjauhan, hanya saja dua-duanya jauh sekali dari kota. Untuk sampai ke kota dan Rumah sakit Rujukan Pertama dibutuhkan waktu sekitar dua setengah jam tanpa macet. Untuk Demografi sendiri, jalanan terdiri dari pegunungan dan kebun teh yang jika ada hujan lebat bisa terjadi longsor sewaktu-waktu. Volume Kendaraan disana masih sedikit sehingga bebas macet. Untuk kendaraannya umum yang digunakan adalah ojeg motor dan bis mini atau dinamakan elf.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Di Puskesmas ‘P’ saya kerja full sebagai fungsional dan belum memegang program apapun. Alasannya, Puskemas pun belum bisa berjalan maksimal karena bangunan masih ngontrak, masih membenahi manajemen dan sistem, serta karyawan yang sudah tebagi-bagi dengan RSUD. Jadi istilahnya baru merintis lagi dari awal. Untuk proses Akreditasi sendiri, Puskesmas ‘P’ akan direncanakan akreditasi akhir tahun 2018 menunggu bangunan baru selesai dibangun. Puksemas ‘P’ sendiri belum terpapar sama sekali mengenai akreditasi oleh Dinas Kesehatan. Lalu pengalaman saya mengenai akreditasinya dapat dari mana? Bukan, bukan PKM ‘P’ yang akan saya ceritakan mengenai pengalamannya tetapi pengalaman akreditasi dari PKM ‘C’&lt;/p&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;Sekitar bulan September 2017, dikarenakan dokter di tempat Puskesmas ‘P’ ada dua orang dan masih ada beberapa Puskesmas yang masih belum ada dokter umumnya, saya dipindahkan kembali oleh Dinas Kesehatan Daerah ke Puskesmas yang letaknya dekat dengan perbatasan Kabupaten Bandung Barat, yaitu Puskesmas ‘C’. Ternyata oh ternyata, Puskesmas tersebut sedang berproses dalam persiapan Akreditasi. Komitmen telah dibentuk pada bulan Februari 2017. Kebetulan awalnya memang ada dokter umum, tetapi bulan Juli 2017 dokter tersebut tidak memperpanjang PTTD-nya, hanya ada dokter THL yang masuk setiap Senin dan Kamis. Dokter THL-pun tidak bisa membantu penuh proses akreditasi karena hari biasa beliau bekerja di RS swasta setempat dan sedang mendaftarkan diri sebagai dokter PTTD juga, sekitar bulan November 2017 dia sudah ditempatkan di PKM yang membutuhkan.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Saya datang ke Puskesmas baru sekitar awal bulan Oktober 2017 karena masih ada pekerjaan yang harus diselesaikan di Puskesmas ‘P’ sebelumnya. Seminggu setelah itu, saya di angkat menjadi ketua UKP. Hanya 3 minggu, waktu persiapan saya untuk mempelajari bab 7, 8, dan 9. Modul Akreditasi pun baru saya dapat dan mulai saya baca. Saat saya cek, bab 7 dan 8 untuk dokumen masih banyak yang belum dilengkapi, terlebih mengenai ‘BUKTI IMPLEMENTASI’ sama sekali belum dikerjakan. Untuk bab 9, sudah dibuat tapi saat saya baca sama sekali tidak ada ‘benang merah’. Di bab 9 saja sudah tidak ada benang merahnya, apalagi benang merah yang disambung dari bab 7 dan 8 sehingga membentuk bab 9. Mungkin sudah bisa ditebak hasilnya bagaimana saat penilaian? Jangankan penilaian, coba Anda bayangkan mengenai prosesnya saja dulu untuk melengkapi hal tersebut. Kami harus bekerja seperti apa? dimana kami ini anggota UKP yang sudah jelas paginya harus melayani masyarakat yang datang untuk berobat terlebih dahulu baru kemudian bisa diskusi tentang dokumen akreditasi. Ah, tapi... sudahlah, tujuan saya disini adalah untuk berbagi Ilmu mengenai akreditasi. Saya tidak peduli, jika memang hasilnya tidak lolos ataupun lolos bersyarat, yang penting saya sudah terpapar akreditasi dan bagaimana setelah ini kita melakukan sesuatu yang lebih baik untuk meningkatan Mutu pelayanan klinis dan keselamatan pasien di Puskesmas tercinta. Alhamdulillah banget jika lolos Madya. Hahaha&lt;/p&gt;.
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Astri Lestari</name></author><summary type="html">Sekadar Informasi, Ini adalah tulisan ketiga saya. Pertama saya nulis itu jika memang moodnya lagi bagus dan lagi ingin nulis. Mungkin catatan nanti saya-Link kan jika mau baca, itu sebenenrnya tulisan iseng dan gak penting sekali yang isinya penuh dengan kesedihan alias depresi. Kedua, mengenai Artikel Ilmiah tentang Diabetes Melitus dan kebetulan dapat Juara pertama di Persadia. Kembali ke judul diatas, tujuan saya menulis di blog ini adalah membahas tentang akreditasi Puskesmas. Apa yang terlintas di benak Anda bagi yang belum terpapar dan sedang mempersiapkan akreditasi Puskesmas? Sebelum menjurus mengenai cerita saya tentang pengalaman Akreditasi, saya akan bercerita terlebih dahulu mengenai latar belakang yang mungkin ada sedikit hubungan dengan yang namanya Akreditasi. Jujur, percaya atau tidak, saya mendengar akreditasi Puskesmas itu sekitar bulan Mei 2017 karena kebetulan saya dipindahkan ke Puskesmas yang sebelumnya saya bekerja di RSUD sebagai dokter Fungsional yang sehari-hari hanya melayani pasien di Poli, IGD, dan Ruang rawat inap. Mungkin Anda juga akan bertanya, “kan sayang banget dari RSUD kok dipindahkan ke Puskesmas?” Jadi begini ceritanya, saya adalah Dokter PTT Daerah sejak 2016, karena RSUD itu baru dibuka. Bangunan RSUD Tipe D itu adalah bekas Puskesmas Kecamatan ‘P’ disana. Setelah selesai dibangun, RSUD membutuhkan banyak dokter umum saat itu, maka oleh Dinas Kesehatan Daerah saya ditempatkan di RSUD dahulu. Setahun kemudian, Puskesmas Kecamatan sudah mendapatkan tempat sementara untuk beroperasi, maka saya dipindahkan ke Puskesmas ‘P’ karena saya tetap memilih mempertahankan status PTTD saya dibanding kontrak di RSUD. Puskesmas dan RSUD letaknya tidak berjauhan, hanya saja dua-duanya jauh sekali dari kota. Untuk sampai ke kota dan Rumah sakit Rujukan Pertama dibutuhkan waktu sekitar dua setengah jam tanpa macet. Untuk Demografi sendiri, jalanan terdiri dari pegunungan dan kebun teh yang jika ada hujan lebat bisa terjadi longsor sewaktu-waktu. Volume Kendaraan disana masih sedikit sehingga bebas macet. Untuk kendaraannya umum yang digunakan adalah ojeg motor dan bis mini atau dinamakan elf. Di Puskesmas ‘P’ saya kerja full sebagai fungsional dan belum memegang program apapun. Alasannya, Puskemas pun belum bisa berjalan maksimal karena bangunan masih ngontrak, masih membenahi manajemen dan sistem, serta karyawan yang sudah tebagi-bagi dengan RSUD. Jadi istilahnya baru merintis lagi dari awal. Untuk proses Akreditasi sendiri, Puskesmas ‘P’ akan direncanakan akreditasi akhir tahun 2018 menunggu bangunan baru selesai dibangun. Puksemas ‘P’ sendiri belum terpapar sama sekali mengenai akreditasi oleh Dinas Kesehatan. Lalu pengalaman saya mengenai akreditasinya dapat dari mana? Bukan, bukan PKM ‘P’ yang akan saya ceritakan mengenai pengalamannya tetapi pengalaman akreditasi dari PKM ‘C’. Sekitar bulan September 2017, dikarenakan dokter di tempat Puskesmas ‘P’ ada dua orang dan masih ada beberapa Puskesmas yang masih belum ada dokter umumnya, saya dipindahkan kembali oleh Dinas Kesehatan Daerah ke Puskesmas yang letaknya dekat dengan perbatasan Kabupaten Bandung Barat, yaitu Puskesmas ‘C’. Ternyata oh ternyata, Puskesmas tersebut sedang berproses dalam persiapan Akreditasi. Komitmen telah dibentuk pada bulan Februari 2017. Kebetulan awalnya memang ada dokter umum, tetapi bulan Juli 2017 dokter tersebut tidak memperpanjang PTTD-nya, hanya ada dokter THL yang masuk setiap Senin dan Kamis. Dokter THL-pun tidak bisa membantu penuh proses akreditasi karena hari biasa beliau bekerja di RS swasta setempat dan sedang mendaftarkan diri sebagai dokter PTTD juga, sekitar bulan November 2017 dia sudah ditempatkan di PKM yang membutuhkan. Saya datang ke Puskesmas baru sekitar awal bulan Oktober 2017 karena masih ada pekerjaan yang harus diselesaikan di Puskesmas ‘P’ sebelumnya. Seminggu setelah itu, saya di angkat menjadi ketua UKP. Hanya 3 minggu, waktu persiapan saya untuk mempelajari bab 7, 8, dan 9. Modul Akreditasi pun baru saya dapat dan mulai saya baca. Saat saya cek, bab 7 dan 8 untuk dokumen masih banyak yang belum dilengkapi, terlebih mengenai ‘BUKTI IMPLEMENTASI’ sama sekali belum dikerjakan. Untuk bab 9, sudah dibuat tapi saat saya baca sama sekali tidak ada ‘benang merah’. Di bab 9 saja sudah tidak ada benang merahnya, apalagi benang merah yang disambung dari bab 7 dan 8 sehingga membentuk bab 9. Mungkin sudah bisa ditebak hasilnya bagaimana saat penilaian? Jangankan penilaian, coba Anda bayangkan mengenai prosesnya saja dulu untuk melengkapi hal tersebut. Kami harus bekerja seperti apa? dimana kami ini anggota UKP yang sudah jelas paginya harus melayani masyarakat yang datang untuk berobat terlebih dahulu baru kemudian bisa diskusi tentang dokumen akreditasi. Ah, tapi... sudahlah, tujuan saya disini adalah untuk berbagi Ilmu mengenai akreditasi. Saya tidak peduli, jika memang hasilnya tidak lolos ataupun lolos bersyarat, yang penting saya sudah terpapar akreditasi dan bagaimana setelah ini kita melakukan sesuatu yang lebih baik untuk meningkatan Mutu pelayanan klinis dan keselamatan pasien di Puskesmas tercinta. Alhamdulillah banget jika lolos Madya. Hahaha.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I believe every human has a finite number of heartbeats. I don’t intend to waste any of mine.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/10/31/heartbeats.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I believe every human has a finite number of heartbeats. I don't intend to waste any of mine." /><published>2017-10-31T10:45:13+07:00</published><updated>2017-10-31T10:45:13+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/10/31/heartbeats</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/10/31/heartbeats.html">&lt;p&gt;Never in all their history have men been able truly to conceive of the world as one: a single sphere, a globe, having the qualities of a globe, a round earth in which all the directions eventually meet, in which there is no center because every point, or none, is center — an equal earth which all men occupy as equals. The airman's earth, if free men make it, will be truly round: a globe in practice, not in theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Science cuts two ways, of course; its products can be used for both good and evil. But there's no turning back from science. The early warnings about technological dangers also come from science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was most significant about the lunar voyage was not that man set foot on the Moon but that they set eye on the earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Chinese tale tells of some men sent to harm a young girl who, upon seeing her beauty, become her protectors rather than her violators. That's how I felt seeing the Earth for the first time. I could not help but love and cherish her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who have seen the Earth from space, and for the hundreds and perhaps thousands more who will, the experience most certainly changes your perspective. The things that we share in our world are far more valuable than those which divide us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;The Final Frontier&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There can be no thought of finishing for ‘aiming for the stars.’ Both figuratively and literally, it is a task to occupy the generations. And no matter how much progress one makes, there is always the thrill of just beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There can be no thought of finishing for ‘aiming for the stars.’ Both figuratively and literally, it is a task to occupy the generations. And no matter how much progress one makes, there is always the thrill of just beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;blockquote&quot;&gt;The dreams of yesterday are the hopes of today and the reality of tomorrow. Science has not yet mastered prophecy. We predict too much for the next year and yet far too little for the next ten.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spaceflights cannot be stopped. This is not the work of any one man or even a group of men. It is a historical process which mankind is carrying out in accordance with the natural laws of human development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Reaching for the Stars&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we got further and further away, it [the Earth] diminished in size. Finally it shrank to the size of a marble, the most beautiful you can imagine. That beautiful, warm, living object looked so fragile, so delicate, that if you touched it with a finger it would crumble and fall apart. Seeing this has to change a man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/Mn9Fa_wQH-M/800x450&quot; alt=&quot;Demo Image&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption text-muted&quot;&gt;To go places and do things that have never been done before – that’s what living is all about.&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Space, the final frontier. These are the voyages of the Starship Enterprise. Its five-year mission: to explore strange new worlds, to seek out new life and new civilizations, to boldly go where no man has gone before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I stand out here in the wonders of the unknown at Hadley, I sort of realize there’s a fundamental truth to our nature, Man must explore, and this is exploration at its greatest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Placeholder text by &lt;a href=&quot;http://spaceipsum.com/&quot;&gt;Space Ipsum&lt;/a&gt;. Photographs by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Astri Lestari</name></author><summary type="html">Never in all their history have men been able truly to conceive of the world as one: a single sphere, a globe, having the qualities of a globe, a round earth in which all the directions eventually meet, in which there is no center because every point, or none, is center — an equal earth which all men occupy as equals. The airman's earth, if free men make it, will be truly round: a globe in practice, not in theory.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Science has not yet mastered prophecy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/10/30/prophecy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Science has not yet mastered prophecy" /><published>2017-10-30T10:45:13+07:00</published><updated>2017-10-30T10:45:13+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/10/30/prophecy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/10/30/prophecy.html">&lt;p&gt;Never in all their history have men been able truly to conceive of the world as one: a single sphere, a globe, having the qualities of a globe, a round earth in which all the directions eventually meet, in which there is no center because every point, or none, is center — an equal earth which all men occupy as equals. The airman's earth, if free men make it, will be truly round: a globe in practice, not in theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Science cuts two ways, of course; its products can be used for both good and evil. But there's no turning back from science. The early warnings about technological dangers also come from science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was most significant about the lunar voyage was not that man set foot on the Moon but that they set eye on the earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Chinese tale tells of some men sent to harm a young girl who, upon seeing her beauty, become her protectors rather than her violators. That's how I felt seeing the Earth for the first time. I could not help but love and cherish her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who have seen the Earth from space, and for the hundreds and perhaps thousands more who will, the experience most certainly changes your perspective. The things that we share in our world are far more valuable than those which divide us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;The Final Frontier&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There can be no thought of finishing for ‘aiming for the stars.’ Both figuratively and literally, it is a task to occupy the generations. And no matter how much progress one makes, there is always the thrill of just beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There can be no thought of finishing for ‘aiming for the stars.’ Both figuratively and literally, it is a task to occupy the generations. And no matter how much progress one makes, there is always the thrill of just beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;blockquote&quot;&gt;The dreams of yesterday are the hopes of today and the reality of tomorrow. Science has not yet mastered prophecy. We predict too much for the next year and yet far too little for the next ten.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spaceflights cannot be stopped. This is not the work of any one man or even a group of men. It is a historical process which mankind is carrying out in accordance with the natural laws of human development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Reaching for the Stars&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we got further and further away, it [the Earth] diminished in size. Finally it shrank to the size of a marble, the most beautiful you can imagine. That beautiful, warm, living object looked so fragile, so delicate, that if you touched it with a finger it would crumble and fall apart. Seeing this has to change a man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/Mn9Fa_wQH-M/800x450&quot; alt=&quot;Demo Image&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption text-muted&quot;&gt;To go places and do things that have never been done before – that’s what living is all about.&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Space, the final frontier. These are the voyages of the Starship Enterprise. Its five-year mission: to explore strange new worlds, to seek out new life and new civilizations, to boldly go where no man has gone before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I stand out here in the wonders of the unknown at Hadley, I sort of realize there’s a fundamental truth to our nature, Man must explore, and this is exploration at its greatest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Placeholder text by &lt;a href=&quot;http://spaceipsum.com/&quot;&gt;Space Ipsum&lt;/a&gt;. Photographs by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Astri Lestari</name></author><summary type="html">Never in all their history have men been able truly to conceive of the world as one: a single sphere, a globe, having the qualities of a globe, a round earth in which all the directions eventually meet, in which there is no center because every point, or none, is center — an equal earth which all men occupy as equals. The airman's earth, if free men make it, will be truly round: a globe in practice, not in theory.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Failure is not an option</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/10/29/exploration.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Failure is not an option" /><published>2017-10-29T10:45:13+07:00</published><updated>2017-10-29T10:45:13+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/10/29/exploration</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/10/29/exploration.html">&lt;p&gt;Never in all their history have men been able truly to conceive of the world as one: a single sphere, a globe, having the qualities of a globe, a round earth in which all the directions eventually meet, in which there is no center because every point, or none, is center — an equal earth which all men occupy as equals. The airman's earth, if free men make it, will be truly round: a globe in practice, not in theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Science cuts two ways, of course; its products can be used for both good and evil. But there's no turning back from science. The early warnings about technological dangers also come from science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was most significant about the lunar voyage was not that man set foot on the Moon but that they set eye on the earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Chinese tale tells of some men sent to harm a young girl who, upon seeing her beauty, become her protectors rather than her violators. That's how I felt seeing the Earth for the first time. I could not help but love and cherish her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who have seen the Earth from space, and for the hundreds and perhaps thousands more who will, the experience most certainly changes your perspective. The things that we share in our world are far more valuable than those which divide us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;The Final Frontier&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There can be no thought of finishing for ‘aiming for the stars.’ Both figuratively and literally, it is a task to occupy the generations. And no matter how much progress one makes, there is always the thrill of just beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There can be no thought of finishing for ‘aiming for the stars.’ Both figuratively and literally, it is a task to occupy the generations. And no matter how much progress one makes, there is always the thrill of just beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;blockquote&quot;&gt;The dreams of yesterday are the hopes of today and the reality of tomorrow. Science has not yet mastered prophecy. We predict too much for the next year and yet far too little for the next ten.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spaceflights cannot be stopped. This is not the work of any one man or even a group of men. It is a historical process which mankind is carrying out in accordance with the natural laws of human development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Reaching for the Stars&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we got further and further away, it [the Earth] diminished in size. Finally it shrank to the size of a marble, the most beautiful you can imagine. That beautiful, warm, living object looked so fragile, so delicate, that if you touched it with a finger it would crumble and fall apart. Seeing this has to change a man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/Mn9Fa_wQH-M/800x450&quot; alt=&quot;Demo Image&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption text-muted&quot;&gt;To go places and do things that have never been done before – that’s what living is all about.&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Space, the final frontier. These are the voyages of the Starship Enterprise. Its five-year mission: to explore strange new worlds, to seek out new life and new civilizations, to boldly go where no man has gone before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I stand out here in the wonders of the unknown at Hadley, I sort of realize there’s a fundamental truth to our nature, Man must explore, and this is exploration at its greatest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Placeholder text by &lt;a href=&quot;http://spaceipsum.com/&quot;&gt;Space Ipsum&lt;/a&gt;. Photographs by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Astri Lestari</name></author><summary type="html">Never in all their history have men been able truly to conceive of the world as one: a single sphere, a globe, having the qualities of a globe, a round earth in which all the directions eventually meet, in which there is no center because every point, or none, is center — an equal earth which all men occupy as equals. The airman's earth, if free men make it, will be truly round: a globe in practice, not in theory.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The dreams of yesterday are the hopes of today and the reality of tomorrow.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/10/28/dreams.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The dreams of yesterday are the hopes of today and the reality of tomorrow." /><published>2017-10-28T10:45:13+07:00</published><updated>2017-10-28T10:45:13+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/10/28/dreams</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/10/28/dreams.html">&lt;p&gt;Never in all their history have men been able truly to conceive of the world as one: a single sphere, a globe, having the qualities of a globe, a round earth in which all the directions eventually meet, in which there is no center because every point, or none, is center — an equal earth which all men occupy as equals. The airman's earth, if free men make it, will be truly round: a globe in practice, not in theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Science cuts two ways, of course; its products can be used for both good and evil. But there's no turning back from science. The early warnings about technological dangers also come from science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was most significant about the lunar voyage was not that man set foot on the Moon but that they set eye on the earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Chinese tale tells of some men sent to harm a young girl who, upon seeing her beauty, become her protectors rather than her violators. That's how I felt seeing the Earth for the first time. I could not help but love and cherish her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who have seen the Earth from space, and for the hundreds and perhaps thousands more who will, the experience most certainly changes your perspective. The things that we share in our world are far more valuable than those which divide us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;The Final Frontier&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There can be no thought of finishing for ‘aiming for the stars.’ Both figuratively and literally, it is a task to occupy the generations. And no matter how much progress one makes, there is always the thrill of just beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There can be no thought of finishing for ‘aiming for the stars.’ Both figuratively and literally, it is a task to occupy the generations. And no matter how much progress one makes, there is always the thrill of just beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;blockquote&quot;&gt;The dreams of yesterday are the hopes of today and the reality of tomorrow. Science has not yet mastered prophecy. We predict too much for the next year and yet far too little for the next ten.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spaceflights cannot be stopped. This is not the work of any one man or even a group of men. It is a historical process which mankind is carrying out in accordance with the natural laws of human development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Reaching for the Stars&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we got further and further away, it [the Earth] diminished in size. Finally it shrank to the size of a marble, the most beautiful you can imagine. That beautiful, warm, living object looked so fragile, so delicate, that if you touched it with a finger it would crumble and fall apart. Seeing this has to change a man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/Mn9Fa_wQH-M/800x450&quot; alt=&quot;Demo Image&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption text-muted&quot;&gt;To go places and do things that have never been done before – that’s what living is all about.&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Space, the final frontier. These are the voyages of the Starship Enterprise. Its five-year mission: to explore strange new worlds, to seek out new life and new civilizations, to boldly go where no man has gone before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I stand out here in the wonders of the unknown at Hadley, I sort of realize there’s a fundamental truth to our nature, Man must explore, and this is exploration at its greatest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Placeholder text by &lt;a href=&quot;http://spaceipsum.com/&quot;&gt;Space Ipsum&lt;/a&gt;. Photographs by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Astri Lestari</name></author><summary type="html">Never in all their history have men been able truly to conceive of the world as one: a single sphere, a globe, having the qualities of a globe, a round earth in which all the directions eventually meet, in which there is no center because every point, or none, is center — an equal earth which all men occupy as equals. The airman's earth, if free men make it, will be truly round: a globe in practice, not in theory.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dinosaurs are extinct today</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/10/27/firstpost.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dinosaurs are extinct today" /><published>2017-10-27T10:45:13+07:00</published><updated>2017-10-27T10:45:13+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/10/27/firstpost</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/10/27/firstpost.html">&lt;p&gt;Never in all their history have men been able truly to conceive of the world as one: a single sphere, a globe, having the qualities of a globe, a round earth in which all the directions eventually meet, in which there is no center because every point, or none, is center — an equal earth which all men occupy as equals. The airman's earth, if free men make it, will be truly round: a globe in practice, not in theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Science cuts two ways, of course; its products can be used for both good and evil. But there's no turning back from science. The early warnings about technological dangers also come from science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was most significant about the lunar voyage was not that man set foot on the Moon but that they set eye on the earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Chinese tale tells of some men sent to harm a young girl who, upon seeing her beauty, become her protectors rather than her violators. That's how I felt seeing the Earth for the first time. I could not help but love and cherish her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who have seen the Earth from space, and for the hundreds and perhaps thousands more who will, the experience most certainly changes your perspective. The things that we share in our world are far more valuable than those which divide us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;The Final Frontier&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There can be no thought of finishing for ‘aiming for the stars.’ Both figuratively and literally, it is a task to occupy the generations. And no matter how much progress one makes, there is always the thrill of just beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There can be no thought of finishing for ‘aiming for the stars.’ Both figuratively and literally, it is a task to occupy the generations. And no matter how much progress one makes, there is always the thrill of just beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;blockquote&quot;&gt;The dreams of yesterday are the hopes of today and the reality of tomorrow. Science has not yet mastered prophecy. We predict too much for the next year and yet far too little for the next ten.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spaceflights cannot be stopped. This is not the work of any one man or even a group of men. It is a historical process which mankind is carrying out in accordance with the natural laws of human development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Reaching for the Stars&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we got further and further away, it [the Earth] diminished in size. Finally it shrank to the size of a marble, the most beautiful you can imagine. That beautiful, warm, living object looked so fragile, so delicate, that if you touched it with a finger it would crumble and fall apart. Seeing this has to change a man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/Mn9Fa_wQH-M/800x450&quot; alt=&quot;Demo Image&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption text-muted&quot;&gt;To go places and do things that have never been done before – that’s what living is all about.&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Space, the final frontier. These are the voyages of the Starship Enterprise. Its five-year mission: to explore strange new worlds, to seek out new life and new civilizations, to boldly go where no man has gone before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I stand out here in the wonders of the unknown at Hadley, I sort of realize there’s a fundamental truth to our nature, Man must explore, and this is exploration at its greatest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Placeholder text by &lt;a href=&quot;http://spaceipsum.com/&quot;&gt;Space Ipsum&lt;/a&gt;. Photographs by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Astri Lestari</name></author><summary type="html">Never in all their history have men been able truly to conceive of the world as one: a single sphere, a globe, having the qualities of a globe, a round earth in which all the directions eventually meet, in which there is no center because every point, or none, is center — an equal earth which all men occupy as equals. The airman's earth, if free men make it, will be truly round: a globe in practice, not in theory.</summary></entry></feed>